■
翻譯  丁小七  章魚X
地球
1988年
翻譯  南鷂北鷹  嘟嘟矢  萊吉
時間軸  Ans
勁歌金曲  第一輯
校對  cazorp  somehacker
片頭特效  脆沙瓤
特效&后期  8T     總監  somehacker
彼得
Peter.
媽媽有話跟你說
Your momma wants to speak with you.
快點  彼得  把這傻玩意兒摘掉
Come on, Pete. Take these fool things off.
寶貝  你怎么又跟別的小孩打架了
Why have you been fighting with the other boys again, baby?
彼得
Peter?
他們弄死了一只無辜的小青蛙
They killed a little frog that ain't done nothing.
用棍子把它捅爛了
Smushed it with a stick.
你真像你爸爸
You're so like your daddy.
長得也很像
You even look like him.
他是個天使
And he was an angel.
-他就是光  -梅
- Composed out of pure light. - Mer?
你不是有禮物要給他嗎
You got a present there for Peter, don't you?
當然
Of course.
給
There.
我幫你放好了  彼得
I've got you covered, Pete.
等我走了以后再打開好嗎
You open it up when I'm gone, okay?
外公他會
Your grandpa...
好好照顧你的
is gonna take such good care of you.
至少在爸爸回來接你之前這段時間
At least until your daddy comes back to get you.
握住我的手
Take my hand.
彼得
Peter.
彼得  過去啊
Pete, come on.
握住我的手
Take my hand.
媽媽
Mom?
不  不  不  不
No! No! No! No!
媽媽  不要走
Mom! No!
-跟我來  -不
- Come with me. - No!
不
No!
待在這里別動  聽話
You've got to stay here. Please.
不要
No...
好嗎
Okay?
不
No.
媽媽
Mom!
漫威影業
┌
┐
└
┘
26年之后
┌
┐
└
┘
┌
┐
└
┘
莫拉格
廢棄星球
銀河護衛隊
放下它
Drop it!
-立刻放下  -哥們兒  沒問題
- Drop it, now! - Hey, cool, man. No problem.
一點問題都沒有
No problem at all.
你怎么知道這東西的
How do you know about this?
我連它是什么都不知道
I don't even know what that is.
我就是個撿破爛的  就隨便翻翻
I'm just a junker, man. I was just checking stuff out.
你可不像撿破爛的
You don't look like a junker.
你穿著掠奪者的制服
You're wearing Ravager garb.
就是件外套而已
This is just an outfit, man.
忍者神龜  你別戳我了
Ninja Turtle, you better stop poking me.
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
我叫彼得·奎爾  兄弟  冷靜點
My name is Peter Quill, okay? Dude, chill out.
-跟我走  -為什么
- Move! - Why?
羅南可能有話要問你
Ronan may have questions for you.
你知道不
Hey, you know what?
你可能聽過我另外一個名字
There's another name you might know me by.
星爵
Star-Lord.
誰
Who?
星爵啊  傳奇俠盜
Star-Lord, man. Legendary outlaw.
-各位  -快走
- Guys? - Move!
算了
Forget this.
彼得
Peter?
出什么事了
What happened?
-布瑞特  -對了布瑞特
- Bereet. - Bereet!
說實話吧  我都忘了你還在這兒
Look, I'm gonna be totally honest with you. I forgot you're here.
克里帝國今天發生了
Scattered riots broke out
多起小規模暴亂
across the Kree Empire today
抗議最近克里大帝
protesting the recent peace treaty
與山達爾的新星至尊簽訂的和平條約
signed by the Kree Emperor and Xandar's Nova Prime.
彼得  有電話找你
Peter, you have call.
-不  等等  別  -奎爾
- No, wait, don't! - Quill?
你好啊  勇度
Hey, Yondu.
我人在莫拉格
I'm here on Morag.
沒看到宇宙靈球也沒看到你
Ain't no Orb, ain't no you.
我之前就在那附近
Well, I was in the neighborhood.
我可幫你解決了個大麻煩
I thought I'd save you the hassle.
那你小子現在在哪
Well, where are you at now, boy?
很抱歉  可我不打算告訴你
I feel really bad about this, but I'm not gonna tell you that.
-我千辛萬苦給你牽了線  -千辛萬苦
- I slaved putting this deal together. - Slaved?
打幾個電話就千辛萬苦了  不是吧
Making a few calls is "slaved"? I mean, really?
你這是要坑我
And now you're gonna rip me off!
我們掠奪者不這么做事  我們有原則
We do not do that to each other. We're Ravagers. We got a code.
原則就是 "能搶就搶"
Yeah, and that code is "steal from everybody."
我從地星把你撿來的時候
When I picked you up on Terra...
"撿來"
"Picked me up."
我手下這些人可是想吃掉你的
these boys of mine wanted to eat you.
是嗎
Yeah?
他們以前沒吃過地星人肉
They ain't never tasted any Terran before.
我制止了他們  你活下來多虧了我
I stopped them. You're alive because of me!
我會找到你的  我要
I will find you, I will...
懸賞捉拿他
Put a bounty on him!
四萬
Forty K.
-但我要捉活的  -是  船長
- But I want him back alive. - Yeah, Cap.
-捉活的  -你沒聽錯
- Alive? - That's what I said.
你撿走他的時候我就跟你說了
I told you when you picked that kid up,
就該按照客戶要求把他送過去
you should have delivered him like we was hired to do!
他不過是我們的貨
He was cargo!
你對他一直太心軟了
You have always been soft on him.
我看是對你太心軟了
You're the only one I'm being soft on!
你別給我操心奎爾先生的事了
Now, don't you worry about Mr. Quill.
一旦把他抓回來
As soon as we get him back here,
我會親手了結他
I'm gonna kill him myself.
我們需要操心的是
What we do need to worry about,
還有誰想得到那個靈球
is who else out there wants that Orb!
┌
┐
└
┘
暗黑星號
克里戰艦
他們稱我為"恐怖分子"
They call me "Terrorist, "
"激進派"  "狂徒"
"Radical", "Zealot",
就因為我謹遵我克里子民的世代法則
because I obey the ancient laws of my people, the Kree,
嚴懲違背法則者
and punish those who do not.
因為我拒絕原諒你們的同族
Because I do not forgive your people
殺死我父親
for taking the life of my father,
父親的父親和祖父的行為
and his father, and his father before him.
我們兩族間持續千年的戰爭永不會被遺忘
A thousand years of war between us will not be forgotten!
你不能這樣  雙方政府簽署了和平條約
You can't do this! Our government signed a peace treaty.
我們的政府沒有羞恥心
My government knows no shame.
山達爾人還有山達爾文明都是禍害
You Xandarians and your culture are a disease.
你
You
永不可能統治山達爾
will never rule Xandar.
不
No.
我是要治愈它
I will cure it!
羅南
Ronan,
克拉斯回來了
Korath has returned.
主人  那人就是個賊
Master, he is a thief,
一個自稱星爵的法外之徒
an outlaw who calls himself Star-Lord.
但我們發現他跟一個叫
But we have discovered he has an agreement
"掮客"的中間人定下協議
to retrieve the Orb for an intermediary
拿回宇宙靈球
known as The Broker.
我跟滅霸保證過幫他拿回宇宙靈球
I promised Thanos I would retrieve the Orb for him.
那樣他才幫我毀滅山達爾
Only then will he destroy Xandar for me.
星云  去山達爾幫我拿到宇宙靈球
Nebula, go to Xandar and get me the Orb.
這將是我的榮幸
It will be my honor.
這將是你的末路
It will be your doom.
要是你再次失敗
If this happens again,
父親可不會給你獎勵
you'll be facing our father without his prize.
我是滅霸的女兒
I'm a daughter of Thanos.
和你一樣
Just like you.
但我對山達爾更熟
But I know Xandar.
羅南已經命令我來...
Ronan has already decreed that I...
不要替我做決定
Do not speak for me.
你不可以失敗
You will not fail.
我失敗過嗎
Have I ever?
┌
┐
└
┘
新星帝國首都
山達爾
山達爾人
Xandarians.
都是一群廢柴
What a bunch of losers.
所有人不是忙著做無聊事
All of them in a big hurry to get from something stupid,
就是做無用功  真令人同情
to nothing at all. Pathetic.
看這個人
Look at this guy!
還管我們叫罪犯
Can you believe they call us criminals,
拿那個發型嚇人才是犯罪
when he's assaulting us with that haircut?
這是什么東西  還自以為多炫酷
What is this thing? Look how it thinks it's so cool.
讓人幫算什么酷
It's not cool to get help!
有本事自己走啊  小怪獸
Walk by yourself, you little gargoyle.
你看那邊的"微笑先生"
Look at Mr. Smiles over here.
你老婆在哪呢  老頭子
Where's your wife, old man?
極品老變態
What a class-A prevert.
是吧  格魯特
Right, Groot?
格魯特
Groot?
別喝噴泉里的水  你個白癡
Don't drink fountain water, you idiot.
太惡心了
That's disgusting!
你喝了  我剛看到了
Yes, you did. I just saw you doing it.
為啥要說謊
Why are you lying?
看來我們有目標了
Looks like we got one.
愚蠢的人類  看看你值多少錢
Okay, humie, how bad does someone wanna find you?
四萬  格魯特  我們要變有錢人了
40,000 units? Groot, we're gonna be rich.
-奎爾先生  -掮客
- Mr. Quill. - Broker.
宇宙靈球
The Orb.
-任務完成  -勇度呢
- As commissioned. - Where's Yondu?
他本來想親自來的  但只能送上問候
Wanted to be here. Sends his love.
同時讓我轉告
And told me to tell you,
你的眉毛是同行里最酷炫的
that you got the best eyebrows in the business.
這是什么意思
What is it?
我不可以透露客戶和他們的要求
It's my policy never to discuss my clients, or their needs.
為了拿到它我可是九死一生
Yeah, well, I almost died getting it for you.
干你們這行就是有這樣的風險
An occupational hazard, I'm sure, in your line of work.
一個機械腦袋怪物
Some machine-headed freak,
自稱是什么羅南的手下
working for a dude named Ronan.
羅南  抱歉了  奎爾先生
Ronan? I'm sorry, Mr. Quill.
真的很抱歉
I truly am.
但凡是跟羅南扯上關系的交易
But I want no part of this transaction
我是不會介入的
if Ronan is involved.
羅南是什么人
Who's Ronan?
一個克里的狂徒  被和平條約所激怒
A Kree fanatic, outraged by the peace treaty,
除非山達爾文明  我的文明被徹底清除
who will not rest until Xandarian culture, my culture,
否則他不會罷休的
is wiped from existence!
-拜托  -他這種人
- Come on. - He's someone
我招惹不起
whose bad side I'd rather not be on.
不是吧  那我就可以招惹嗎
What? What about my bad side?
再會無期  奎爾先生
Farewell, Mr. Quill.
我們有約定在先的  老兄
Hey, we had a deal, Bro!
怎么了
What happened?
這家伙翻臉不認賬
This guy just backed out of a deal on me.
我最討厭的就是不守信用的男人
If there's one thing I hate, it's a man without integrity.
彼得·奎爾  大家都叫我星爵
Peter Quill. People call me Star-Lord.
看得出你是個正人君子
You have the bearing of a man of honor.
我也沒那么好啦
Well, you know, I wouldn't say that.
大家倒都這么說我
People say it about me, all the time,
不過我一般不會這么夸自己
but it's not something I would ever say about myself.
這就不能怪我了
This wasn't the plan.
把他裝進袋子  把他裝進袋子
Put him in the bag. Put him in the bag!
不  不是她  是他
No! Not her, him!
要分清性別啊
Learn genders, man.
不帶咬人的
Biting? That's not fair!
放松
Take it easy!
蠢貨  你該長點記性
Fool. You should have learned.
我從不長記性  缺點之一
I don't learn. One of my issues.
搞什...
What the...
別笑了  白癡  表現得專業點
Quit smiling, you idiot. You're supposed to be a professional.
饒了我吧
You gotta be kidding me.
我滿足起來很容易
I live for the simple things.
比如想想這樣會有多疼
Like how much this is gonna hurt.
沒錯  顫抖吧  凡人
Yeah. Writhe, little man.
還會再長出來的  你個二缺
It'll grow back, you d'ast idiot.
別嚶嚶了
Quit whining.
實驗體89P13  放下武器
Subject 89P13, drop your weapon.
該死
Aw, crap.
以新星軍團的名義
By the authority of the Nova Corps,
-你們被逮捕了  -好了  站起來
- you are under arrest... - All right. Come on up.
罪名是危害他人生命及破壞財產
for endangerment to life and the destruction of property.
這不是星王子嗎
Hey! If it isn't Star-Prince.
-星爵  -抱歉了爵爺
- Star-Lord. - Sorry. "Lord."
我之前因為小偷小摸抓過他
I picked this guy up a while back for petty theft.
他還有個代號呢
He's got a code name.
請讓開
Yeah. Stay out of the way.
拜托  一聽就是個大盜的名字啊
Come on, man. It's a... It's an outlaw name.
沒事的  小哥
Just relax, pal.
有代號挺酷的  也沒有很奇怪了
It's cool to have a code name. It's not that weird.
法西斯
Fascists.
┌
┐
└
┘
山達爾武裝部隊
新星總部
羅南正在全星系
Ronan is destroying
摧毀山達爾人在各處建立的前哨站
Xandarian outposts throughout the galaxy.
我認為這應該值得
I should think that would call
克里方面稍稍作出一些回應吧
for some slight response on the part of the Kree.
我們已經簽訂和平條約了  新星至尊
We signed your peace treaty, Nova Prime.
你還想要什么
What more do you want?
至少克里帝國方面
At least a statement from the Kree Empire
應該譴責他的行為
saying that they condemn his actions.
他正在屠殺兒童
He is slaughtering children.
破壞家庭
Families.
這就是你們的事了
That is your business.
我現在還有其他事要忙
Now, I have other matters to attend to.
混蛋
Prick.
好消息
Well, some good news.
我們好像逮捕了羅南的同伙
It looks like we've apprehended one of Ronan's compatriots.
卡魔拉
Gamora.
經受過全身改造  訓練成了殺人機器
Surgically modified and trained as a living weapon.
"瘋狂泰坦"滅霸的養女
The adopted daughter of the Mad Titan, Thanos.
最近滅霸派她和星云姐妹兩人去輔佐羅南
Recently, Thanos lent her and her sister Nebula out to Ronan,
因此我們有理由相信
which leads us to believe
滅霸和羅南有勾結
that Thanos and Ronan are working together.
實驗體89P13  自稱"火箭"
Subject 89P13. Calls itself "Rocket."
在低等生命體上
The result of illegal genetic
進行非法基因改造和機械實驗的產物
and cybernetic experiments on a lower life form.
什么鬼東西
What the hell?
他們叫它"格魯特"
They call it "Groot."
近來作為89P13的私人植物及打手
A humanoid plant that's been travelling recently
陪伴其行動的類人植物
as 89P13's personal houseplant/muscle.
彼得·杰森·奎爾  來自地星
Peter Jason Quill, from Terra.
自幼被勇度·尤冬塔領導的傭兵組織"掠奪者"
Raised from youth by a band of mercenaries called the Ravagers,
撫養成人
led by Yondu Udonta.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不知道這機器是怎么運作的
I didn't know how this machine worked.
真是一幫子混球
What a bunch of a-holes.
把四個都送到克林去
Transport all four to the Kyln.
┌
┐
└
┘
高安保級別監獄
克林
我猜新星軍團成員一般都遵紀守法
I guess most of Nova Corps wanna uphold the laws,
可這里這些人腐敗又殘忍
but these ones here, they're corrupt and cruel.
反正我是不用擔心
But, hey, that's not my problem.
我待不了多久的
I ain't gonna be here long.
我越過22次獄  這個也不例外
I've escaped 22 prisons. This one's no different.
這個妞出現是算你走運
You're lucky the broad showed up,
不然我和格魯特
because otherwise, me and Groot
現在已經拿到賞金了
would be collecting that bounty right now,
至于你  已經被勇度和那些掠奪者
and you'd be getting drawn and quartered
五馬分尸了
by Yondu and those Ravagers.
這些年想殺我的人可太多了
I've had a lot of folks try to kill me over the years.
怎么可能被一棵樹和一只會說話的浣熊拿下
I ain't about to be brought down by a tree and a talking raccoon.
等等
Hold.
-浣熊是什么鬼  -浣熊是什么鬼
- What's a raccoon? - "What's a raccoon?"
你自己就是啊  傻貨
It's what you are, stupid.
老子是這世上獨一無二的
Ain't no thing like me, except me.
這個宇宙靈球是《死吻》中的神秘箱子
So, this Orb has a real shiny blue suitcase,
《奪寶奇兵》里的約柜
Ark of the Covenant,
還是《馬耳他雄鷹》里的雕像啊
Maltese Falcon sort of vibe.
-到底是什么  -我是格魯特
- What is it? - I am Groot.
所以呢  那個宇宙靈球是什么
So what? What's the Orb?
我對陰險的小偷沒什么好說的
I have no words for an honorless thief.
你還是個想滅絕別人的瘋子的走狗呢
Pretty high and mighty coming from the lackey
真理直氣壯
of a genocidal maniac.
對  我知道你是誰
Yeah, I know who you are.
大家都知道你是誰
Anyone who's anyone knows who you are.
對  我們知道你是誰
Yeah, we know who you are.
-她是誰  -我是格魯特
- Who is she? - I am Groot.
你已經說過了
Yeah, you said that.
我不是來幫羅南拿回宇宙靈球的
I wasn't retrieving the Orb for Ronan.
我背叛了他
I was betraying him.
我已經私下跟第三方買家談好了
I had an agreement to sell it to a third party.
我是格魯特
I am Groot.
你這句話說得
Well, that's just as fascinating
跟之前89次一樣令人耳目一新
as the first 89 times you told me that.
這愛心樹什么毛病
What is wrong with Giving Tree, here?
他沒法像你我這樣正常說話
Well, he don't know talking good like me and you.
所以他的詞庫里只有"我"
So his vocabulistics is limited to "I"
"是"和"格魯特"三個詞
and "am" and "Groot."
順序亂了都不行
Exclusively in that order.
你知道嗎  我的忍耐就要到極限了
I tell you what, that's gonna wear real thin, real fast.
給我放下
Put that away.
你個藍皮怪  把那耳機摘下來
Listen to me, you big blue bastard. Take those headphones off.
那是我的  應該被扣押起來的
That's mine. Those belong to impound.
那磁帶還有播放器  都是我的
That tape and that player is mine!
那是1973年藍色瑞典人的
Hooked on a Feeling,
《迷上一種感覺》
Blue Swede, 1973.
那是屬于我的歌
That song belongs to me!
-你死定了  你死定了  -兇手
- You first! You first! - Murderer!
老子先宰了你  卡魔拉  你死定了
Coming for you first, Gamora! You're dead!
你個垃圾  賤貨
You're scum! You're scum!
我說過吧
It's like I said,
她名頭響著呢
she's got a rep.
這里有好多囚犯的親人
A lot of prisoners here have lost their families
都死在了羅南和他的狗腿子手下
to Ronan and his goons.
她最多撐一天
She'll last a day, tops.
殺人犯
Murderer!
警衛會保護她的吧
The guards will protect her, right?
他們只管阻止我們逃出去
They're here to stop us from getting out.
在里面怎么作死他們才不管
They don't care what we do to each other inside.
無論未來有什么大風大浪
Whatever nightmares the future holds,
跟我的經歷比起來  也都是
are dreams compared to what's behind me.
瞧瞧這個新來的鮮肉
Check out the new meat.
我要把你渾身抹滿古納維恩液
I'm gonna slather you up in Gunavian jelly,
然后好好爽一發
and go to town...
先把話說清楚
Let's make something clear.
這小子的菊花是我們的
This one here is our booty!
你們想動他
You wanna get to him,
先過我們這一關
you go through us!
或者  說得更準確些
Or, more accurately,
我們先做了你
we go through you.
我是他們的
I'm with them.
我恨你們
I hate you.
再結實的牢房也別想保你的命
No cell's gonna protect you for long.
你死定了
You're dead!
死定了
Dead!
把她帶到浴室去
Take her down to the showers.
那里血跡容易清理
It'll be easier to clean up the blood down there.
奎爾  你干什么去
Quill, where you going?
奎爾
Quill.
Quill!
卡魔拉  我現在宣判你的死刑
Gamora, consider this a death sentence
為你對全銀河系犯下的罪行償命吧
for your crimes against the galaxy.
你敢
You dare?
你知道我是誰吧
You know who I am, yes?
你是德拉克斯
You're Drax.
毀滅者
The Destroyer.
奎爾
Quill!
你知道我這名號怎么來的吧
And you know why they call me this.
你宰過羅南手下數十個惡棍
You slayed dozens of Ronan's minions.
羅南殺了我妻子  奧薇特
Ronan murdered my wife, Ovette,
還有我女兒  卡瑪莉亞
and my daughter, Camaria.
他將她們殘殺致死
He slaughtered them where they stood.
但他卻笑了
And he laughed!
奎爾
Quill?
她的命
Her life
輪不著你們來取
is not yours to take.
他殺了我家人
He killed my family.
我也要殺了他的家人
I shall kill one of his in return.
當然好  德拉克斯  給你  我
Of course, Drax. Here, I...
奎爾  你干什么
Quill! What are you doing?
我絕不是羅南或滅霸的家人
I'm no family to Ronan or Thanos.
我是你阻止他的唯一希望
I'm your only hope at stopping him.
女人  你的話對我一文不值
Woman, your words mean nothing to me!
-別  別別別別  -見鬼
- Hey! Hey, hey, hey! Hey! - Crap.
如果你的目標是殺了羅南
You know, if killing Ronan is truly your sole purpose,
殺了她也沒法幫你實現目標
I don't think this is the best way to go about it.
這賤女人不是也刺殺過你嗎
Are you not the man this wench attempted to kill?
反正她也不是第一個
Well, I mean, she's hardly the first woman
想殺我的女人了
to try and do that to me.
你看  這疤是一個巨火辣的拉賈克妞弄的
Look, this is from a smoking-hot Rajak girl.
拿叉子戳出來的
Stabbed me with a fork.
她不樂意我大清早就離她而去
Didn't like me skipping out on her at sunrise.
這條疤是因為有個克里妞想把我的胸腔破開
I got, right here, a Kree girl tried to rip out my thorax.
我在和新星檔案處
She caught me with this
一個瘦瘦的阿斯卡瓦里安妞
skinny little A'askavariian
鬼混時被她抓包了
who worked in Nova Records.
我只是想套些消息而已
I was trying to get information.
你見過阿斯卡瓦里安人吧
You ever see an A'askavariian?
她們長著觸角  牙齒跟針一樣
They have tentacles, and needles for teeth.
你覺得我真會看上...
If you think I'm seriously interested in that, then...
好吧你不在乎  但我想說的是
You don't care. But here's the point.
她背叛了羅南  他會來追殺她
She betrayed Ronan. He's coming back for her.
等他自己找過來
And when he does,
到時你就可以
that's when you...
我為什么要把手指放在他的喉嚨上
Why would I put my finger on his throat?
啥
What?
這只是個手勢
No, it's a symbol.
這個手勢表示你割了他的喉嚨
This is a symbol for you slicing his throat.
我才不想割他的喉嚨
I would not slice his throat.
我會一刀砍了他的腦袋
I would cut his head clean off.
這是通用手勢啊  意思是殺人
It's a general expression for you killing somebody.
你聽說過  見過這手勢  對吧
You've heard of this. You've seen this, right?
-你知道這什么意思吧  -知道  知道
- You know what that is. - Yeah. Yeah.
-人人都知道  -不知道  不知道
- Everyone knows. - No, no.
我就是想說  你最好留她一命
What I'm saying is, you want to keep her alive.
別幫你敵人的忙
Don't do his work for him.
我喜歡你的刀  我收下了
I like your knife. I'm keeping it.
-那是人家最喜歡的刀  -聽著
- That was my favorite knife. - Listen!
我才懶得管你是死是活
I could care less whether you live or whether you die.
-那你攔下那大個子干什么  -簡單
- Then why stop the big guy? - Simple.
你知道能把宇宙靈球賣給誰
You know where to sell my Orb.
我們和那東西都困在這里  你怎么賣
How are we gonna sell it when we and it are still here?
我這位火箭老兄
My friend Rocket, here,
成功越獄22次
has escaped 22 prisons.
我們肯定出得去
We're getting out.
然后我們直奔勇度那里去取你的賞金
And then we're headed straight to Yondu to retrieve your bounty.
你那買家打算花多少錢買我的宇宙靈球
How much was your buyer willing to pay you for my Orb?
四十億
Four billion units.
-多少  -我操
- What? - Holy shit.
宇宙靈球是我逃離滅霸和羅南的機會
That Orb is my opportunity to get away from Thanos and Ronan.
如果你能越獄
If you free us,
我就直接帶你去見買家
I'll lead you to the buyer directly
賣的錢我們三個平分
and I'll split the profit between the three of us.
我是格魯特
I am Groot.
四人平分
Four of us.
出事兒了睡大覺  一聽見錢就來精神
Asleep for the danger, awake for the money,
死性不改
as per frickin' usual.
你被背叛了  羅南
You have been betrayed, Ronan.
我們只知道她被捉住了
We know only that she has been captured.
卡魔拉也許還有機會取回宇宙靈球
Gamora may yet recover the Orb.
錯  我們在克林的線人
No! Our sources within the Kyln
說卡魔拉對宇宙靈球自有打算
say Gamora has her own plans for the Orb.
你跟滅霸的合作
Your partnership with Thanos
已經岌岌可危了
is at risk.
滅霸要見你  現在就見
Thanos requires your presence. Now!
┌
┐
└
┘
圣域
滅霸領地
恕我直言  滅霸
With all due respect, Thanos,
是你女兒惹下的麻煩
your daughter made this mess,
你卻傳喚我過來
and yet you summon me.
你最好說話小聲些  指控者
I would lower my voice, Accuser.
她先是敗在一群原始人手下
First, she lost a battle with some primitive.
滅霸把卡魔拉交由你調遣
Thanos put Gamora under your charge.
然后還被新星軍團送進大牢
Then she was apprehended by the Nova Corps.
現在空口無憑的人是你
You are the one here with nothing to show for it.
是你的線人說她早已謀劃背叛我們
Your sources say that she meant to betray us the whole time!
放尊重點
Lower your tone!
我雖是你的
I may be your...
我只希望您把這當回事
I only ask that you take this matter seriously.
小子  我不當回事的
The only matter I do not take seriously, boy,
只有你了
is you.
你的政治權術真無聊
Your politics bore me.
你做事像個鬧脾氣的孩子
Your demeanor is that of a pouty child.
而且很顯然
And, apparently,
是你逼走了我最愛的女兒  卡魔拉
you alienated my favorite daughter, Gamora.
我會踐行我們的約定的  克里人
I shall honor our agreement, Kree,
但你務必將宇宙靈球帶給我
if you bring me the Orb.
如果下次見我時你再兩手空空
But return to me again empty-handed,
我就用你的血染紅整個星系
and I will bathe the starways in your blood.
多謝了  父親  很公平
Thanks, Dad. Sounds fair.
這場爭斗你贏不了
This is one fight you won't win.
我們去克林吧
Let's head to the Kyln.
如果我們想逃出去
If we're gonna get out of here,
得設法進到那邊的瞭望塔里
we're gonna need to get into that watchtower.
為此我需要幾件東西
And to do that, I'm gonna need a few things.
警衛都佩戴著安保臂帶
The guards wear security bands
來控制人員進出  我要一個
to control their ins and outs. I need one.
交給我
Leave it to me.
那邊那位  我需要他的假腿
That dude, there. I need his prosthetic leg.
-他的腿  -對
- His leg? - Yeah.
其他的部分我可不需要
God knows I don't need the rest of him.
瞧瞧他  廢物
Look at him, he's useless.
好吧
All right.
最后一樣  后邊的墻上
And finally, on the wall back there
有塊黑色面板  閃著黃燈的
is a black panel. Blinky yellow light.
-瞧見了沒  -看見了
- Do you see it? - Yeah.
里面有塊柯尼斯電池
There's a quarnyx battery behind it.
紫顏色的  接著綠色電線
Purplish box, green wires.
要想進瞭望塔  我需要這東西
To get into that watchtower, I definitely need it.
要怎么才能拿到
How are we supposed to do that?
這群禿頭佬應該覺得你挺美
Well, supposably, these bald-bodies find you attractive.
所以你可以色誘一個
So, maybe you can work out some sort of trade.
你逗樂呢吧
You must be joking.
沒有  我真聽他們說你挺美
No, I really heard they find you attractive.
你看  那東西離地20英尺
Look, it's 20 feet up in the air,
而且還處在
and it's in the middle of
一座戒備森嚴的監獄正中央
the most heavily-guarded part of the prison.
想要不被發現  絕不可能
It's impossible to get up there without being seen.
我想了個計劃
I got one plan,
而這計劃他媽的還就需要柯尼斯電池
and that plan requires a frickin' quarnyx battery,
所以你給我想辦法去
so figure it out!
我接著說了哈  多謝
Can I get back to it? Thanks.
接下來這點非常重要
Now, this is important.
一旦電池被取下來
Once the battery is removed,
監獄就會進入警戒狀態
everything is gonna slam into emergency mode.
所以一旦得手  就必須迅速行動
Once we have it, we gotta move quickly,
因此務必在最后一步再取下電池
so you definitely need to get that last.
或者先拿電池  再隨機應變
Or we could just get it first and improvise.
-我去取臂帶  -我去拿腿
- I'll get the armband. - Leg.
囚犯
Prisoner,
立即放下該設備  退回監房
drop the device immediately and retreat to your cell,
否則我們就開火了
or we will open fire.
我  是
I am
格魯特
Groot!
開火
Fire!
所有囚犯立即返回休息區
All prisoners return to your sleeping areas.
你個白癡
You idiot!
家伙不在手上  我怎么跟這些東西打
How am I supposed to fight these things without my stuff?
是那動物在指揮
The animal is in control.
聽我命令準備開火
Fire on my command!
猥瑣的小怪物
Creepy little beast!
這才像話
Yeah.
你想要我的啥
You need my what?
-把這個給我  -請便吧
- I'll need this. - Good luck.
這是內置在體內的
It's internally wired.
我自有辦法
I'll figure something out.
把腿放下
Drop the leg!
把腿放下  回到自己監房去
Drop the leg and move back to your cell!
火箭
Rocket!
朝瞭望塔前進
Move to the watchtower!
你
You!
睡過阿斯卡瓦里安人的男人
Man who has lain with an A'askavariian!
就那么一次而已
It was one time, man.
所有待命警衛請全副武裝
We need all available guards in full combat gear...
不要怨恨地盯著我  女人
Spare me your foul gaze, woman.
這家伙來干什么
Why is this one here?
我們答應了
We promised him he could
讓他跟著我們  直到手刃了你老大
stay by your side until he kills your boss.
我向來信守承諾
I always keep my promises,
尤其是面對一個肌肉呆男
when they're to muscle-bound whack-jobs
我不同意就宰了我的時候  給你
who will kill me if I don't. Here you go.
腿我是開玩笑的
I was just kidding about the leg.
我只需要這兩樣東西
I just need these two things.
-什么  -我就覺著會挺好笑啊
- What? - No, I thought it'd be funny.
多好笑啊
Was it funny?
等等  他單腿跳是個什么樣子
Wait, what did he look like hopping around?
我可是花了三萬塊買的他的腿
I had to transfer him 30,000 units!
我們要怎么逃脫
How are we going to leave?
他想好計劃了
Well, he's got a plan.
有的吧  難道也是編出來逗人玩的
Right? Or is that another thing you made up?
有計劃的  我有計劃的
I have a plan! I have a plan!
別再唧唧歪歪的了
Cease your yammering
趕緊帶我們沖出這惱人的監牢吧
and relieve us from this irksome confinement.
這回我跟這個活字典
Yeah, I'll have to agree with the walking thesaurus
看法相同
on that one.
不準再叫我字典
Do not ever call me a thesaurus.
就是個比喻而已  哥們
It's just a metaphor, dude.
他們只能理解字面意思
His people are completely literal.
弄個比喻就繞暈了
Metaphors are gonna go over his head.
我怎么繞都不暈的
Nothing goes over my head.
我的反應特別快  肯定能走出去
My reflexes are too fast. I would catch it.
我要全銀河最蠢的人死在一起了
I'm gonna die surrounded by the biggest idiots in the galaxy.
那些槍威力可不小
Those are some big guns.
聽我號令
On my command!
第一發
Number one!
耗子  你的計劃呢
Rodent, we are ready for your plan.
急什么
Hold on!
第二發
Number two!
我認得這種動物
I recognize this animal.
我們小時候會拿來架在火上烤
We'd roast them over a flame pit as children.
肉質相當鮮美
Their flesh was quite delicious.
幫倒忙呢你
Not helping!
第三發
Number three!
全體聽我號令
All fire on my command!
三
Three!
二
Two!
一
One!
他把人工重力關掉了
He turned off the artificial gravity,
除了這座瞭望塔里的
everywhere but in here.
我就說我有計劃
I told you I had a plan.
這計劃真是太完美了
That was a pretty good plan.
太好了  在那邊  去開我的飛船
Yeah! There it is. Get my ship.
米拉諾號  那邊角落里橙藍相間的那艘
It's the Milano, the orange and blue one over in the corner.
居然把我的褲子卷成一團
They crumpled my pants up into a ball.
真沒禮貌  你們的都是疊好了的
That's rude! They folded yours.
宇宙靈球在里面呢  快走
The Orb's there. Let's go.
-等下  等下等下  -怎么了
- Wait, wait, wait. - What?
那混蛋沒放回來
That bastard didn't put it back.
-什么沒放回來  -拿著
- Put what back? - Here.
帶到船上去  我隨后就到
Get them to the ship. I will be right back.
你打算怎么
How are you gonna possibly...
讓米拉諾號停在附近就行
Just keep the Milano close by.
走吧
Go.
快走啊
Go!
我的脖子
My neck!
他打算怎么跟我們會合
Well, how's he gonna get to us?
他拒絕向我透露相關信息
He declined to share that information with me.
那就去他的
Well, screw this, then!
我才不想傻等一個作死的人類
I ain't waiting around for some humie with a death wish.
宇宙靈球在你手上呢  是吧
You got the Orb, right?
對
Yes.
如果現在再不走  我們會被轟成渣的
If we don't leave now, we will be blown to bits.
不行
No!
宇宙靈球沒到手決不能走
We're not leaving without the Orb.
快看
Behold.
你果然有膽識
This one shows spirit.
在和羅南對戰時肯定是個得力幫手
He shall make a keen ally in the battle against Ronan.
朋友  你回去拿什么了
Companion, what were you retrieving?
真是個蠢材
You're an imbecile.
浣熊形象的卡通人物
游俠瑞克  你這是在干嘛
Yo, Ranger Rick! What are you doing?
你怎么沒經過同意就拆我的飛船
You can't take apart my ship without asking me!
-這是什么  -別碰那個
- See, what is this? - Don't touch that!
是個炸彈
It's a bomb.
-炸彈?  -對
- A bomb? - Yup.
你就把炸彈那樣放著
And you leave it lying around?
我本來打算找個盒子放進去的
I was gonna put it in a box.
放到盒子里有用嗎
What's a box gonna do?
-這個怎么樣  -不行
- How about this one? - No! Hey!
-別碰  -為什么  這是什么
- Leave it alone. - Why? What is it?
閉嘴
Shut up.
那個是什么
What is that?
這是在萬分危急時候用的
That's for if things get really hardcore.
或者想炸衛星時候用的
Or if you wanna blow up moons.
我不會讓你們炸衛星
No one's blowing up moons.
樂趣都被你抹殺光了
You just wanna suck the joy out of everything.
我需要你聯系的買家坐標
So, listen, I'm gonna need your buyer's coordinates.
暫時來說  我們的航行方向沒有問題
We're heading in the right direction. For now.
如果你真想合作的話
If we're gonna work together,
至少試著多信任我點
you might try trusting me a little bit.
那你有多信任我
And how much do you trust me?
如果你告訴我這是什么
I'd trust you a lot more
我就能更信任你
if you told me what this was.
我猜這是某種武器
Because I'm guessing it's some kind of weapon.
我也不知道這是什么
I don't know what it is.
如果真是武器  那就能用來對付羅南了
If it's a weapon, we should use it against Ronan.
快放下  你個傻子  你會害死我們的
Put it down, you fool. You'll destroy us all.
只想害死你  女殺手
Or just you, murderess!
我可救了你一次  小娘子
I let you live once, princess!
我才不是娘子
I am not a princess!
在我的飛船上別鬧出人命
Nobody is killing anybody on my ship!
我們得團結一致拿到錢
We're stuck together until we get the money.
我可不是為了錢
I have no interest in money.
棒極了
Great.
那我們三個又能多分點了
That means more money for the three of us.
我們四個
For the four of us.
伙伴們
Partners.
我們是有約在先
We have an agreement,
但我絕不會做你這種人的伙伴
but I would never be partners with the likes of you.
我去通知買家我們在路上了
I'll tell the buyer we're on our way.
奎爾  你的船真惡心
And Quill, your ship is filthy.
這才哪到哪
She has no idea.
用黑光燈一照
If I had a black light,
整艘飛船里都是我的涂鴉
the place would look like a Jackson Pollock painting.
美國抽象表現主義畫家  以"滴灑"作畫聞名
你該吃藥了  奎爾
You got issues, Quill.
我發誓  我真的不知道他們去哪了
I swear. I don't know where they went! I swear.
如果他知道的話
If he knew where they were headed,
早就告訴我們了
he would have already told us.
羅南
Ronan,
新星軍團派了一支艦隊過來守衛監獄
the Nova Corps sent a fleet to defend the prison.
那好吧
Well, then,
派死靈艦去找遍宇宙的每個角落
send Necrocraft to every corner of the quadrant.
給我找到靈球
Find the Orb.
不惜一切代價
Any means, any price.
這里怎么處置
And this place?
不能讓新星知道我們在找什么
The Nova can't know what we're after.
全部解決了
Cleanse it!
你這兒還有這種可愛的小玩意嗎
Do you got any other cute little buggers like this one?
我要在我的控制臺旁擺一排
I like to stick 'em all in a row on my control console.
我分辨不出您是開玩笑還是認真的
I can't tell if you're joking or not.
他非常認真的
He's being fully serious.
那么我可以給您看看
In that case, I can show you...
但是你得先告訴我宇宙靈球到底是干嘛的
But first, you gonna tell me what this Orb is,
為什么每個人都他媽為之瘋狂
and why everybody cares so damn much about it.
然后你還得告訴我
And then you gonna tell me,
真正的買家是誰
who out there might wanna buy it.
先生  高端客戶群是...
Sir, the high-end community is a...
高端客戶群是...
The high-end community is a...
是一個嚴格
It's a tight-knit...
嚴格的
Tight-knit...
高端客戶群是一個嚴格的...
The high-end community is a very tight-knit...
我不可能出賣
I cannot possibly betray
買家的機密信息
the confidentiality of my buyers!
你再說說看誰是你的買家
Now, who again is this buyer of yours?
卡瑞娜
Carina.
請吩咐  主人
Yes, Master.
你們種族的人是有胳膊有肘的吧
Your people do have elbows, do they not?
是的  主人
We do, Master.
那就好好利用起來
Then use them.
我用不著提醒你
I don't have to remind you
上一個讓我失望的侍從有什么下場了吧
what happened to the last attendant who disappointed me.
對嗎
Do I?
快點快點  我們的客人馬上就要到了
Chop, chop. Our guests will be here soon.
當心  我們要著陸了
Heads up! We're inbound.
這是哪
What is it?
他們稱之為無存知地
It's called Knowhere.
原本是個遠古天神的頭顱
The severed head of an ancient celestial being.
小心駛入  耗子
Be wary headed in, rodent.
這里毫無秩序可言
There are no regulations whatsoever here.
┌
┐
└
┘
礦場
無存知地
數百年前  蒂萬集團派遣工人
Hundreds of years ago, the Tivan Group sent workers in
來開采這個頭骨中的有機物
to mine the organic matter within the skull.
骨頭  腦組織  還有脊髓液
Bone, brain tissue, spinal fluid.
都是稀缺資源
All rare resources,
不管在哪的黑市都能買上好價錢
highly valued in black markets across the galaxy.
這工作既危險又違法
It's dangerous and illegal work,
只適合亡命徒
suitable only for outlaws.
我本人就來自一個無法無天的星球
Well, I come from a planet of outlaws.
比利小子  邦尼和克萊德
Billy the Kid, Bonnie and Clyde,
均為美國家喻戶曉的傳奇罪犯
約翰·斯塔莫斯
John Stamos.
80年代著名演員  彼得被劫走同年他主演的《歡樂滿屋》正在播放
聽起來真不錯  我倒想去瞧瞧
It sounds like a place, which I would like to visit.
是挺值得去
Yeah, you should.
打擾下
Excuse me.
-看緊錢包  -能給點錢嗎
- Watch your wallets. - Can you spare any units?
快走開
Get out of here.
你的買家就在這里面
Your buyer's in there?
我們在這兒等他的代表
We are to wait here for his representative.
滾出去
Get out of here!
這可不是個體面的地方
This is no respectable establishment.
我們等待期間還能做點什么
What do you expect us to do while we wait?
好樣的  好樣的
Yes! Yes!
我的奧羅尼贏了
My Orloni has won,
我樣樣都是第一
as I won at all things!
再多灌點這液體吧
Now, let's put more of this liquid into our bodies.
你只有這句感覺沒有那么瘋
That's the first thing you said that wasn't bat-shit crazy!
天哪  他們這的燃料貴死了
Man, you wouldn't believe what they charge for fuel out here.
搞不好到最后我還得賠錢
I might actually lose money on this job.
我的聯系人讓我們先等著
My connection is making us wait.
只是種談判策略  相信我  這我在行
It's just a negotiation tactic. Trust me, this is my specialty.
而你的風格是那種
Where yours is more,
左一刀  右一刀  這就是我的條件
"Stab, stab. Those are my terms."
我父親沒教過我怎么給人施壓
My father didn't stress diplomacy.
滅霸嗎
Thanos?
他不是我父親
He's not my father.
滅霸入侵了我的母星
When Thanos took my home world,
在我面前殺了我父母
he killed my parents in front of me.
他折磨我
He tortured me,
把我改造成殺人機器
turned me into a weapon.
當他說要幫羅南摧毀整個星球時
When he said he was going to destroy an entire planet for Ronan,
我不能袖手旁觀  所以
I couldn't stand by and...
為什么要冒著生命危險去取它
Why would you risk your life for this?
我母親給我的
My mother gave it to me.
我媽媽喜歡和我分享
My mom liked sharing with
她年輕時喜歡的流行歌曲
me all the pop songs that she loved growing up.
碰巧我那天帶在身上
I happened to have it on me,
那天我...
when I was...
那天她...
The day that she...
就是我離開地球那天
You know, when I left Earth.
你都用它做什么
What do you do with it?
做什么  什么都不做  只要去聽
Do? Nothing. You listen to it.
你也可以跟著跳
Or you can dance.
我是名戰士也是個殺手  我從不跳舞
I'm a warrior and an assassin. I do not dance.
真的嗎
Really?
在我母星  有個關于你這樣的人的傳說
On my planet, there's a legend about people like you.
叫做
It's called
《渾身是勁》
Footloose.
凱文·貝肯的歌舞電影
講述的是舞者用舞技打破小城禁忌的故事
故事講的是一個叫
And in it, a great hero
凱文·貝肯的大英雄
named Kevin Bacon,
教會那個城市里
teaches an entire city full of people
所有的假正經[菊花塞著棍子]跳舞
with sticks up their butts that dancing, well...
是件很偉大的事
It's the greatest thing there is.
誰把棍子插進他們菊花里
Who put the sticks up their butts?
什么  不  這只是個...
What? No, that's just a...
-太殘忍了  -這只是個俗語
- That is cruel. - It's just a phrase
大家都知道
people use.
旋律挺美的
The melody is pleasant!
-不  -搞什么
- No! - What the hell?
我知道你是什么樣的人  彼得·奎爾
I know who you are, Peter Quill!
我是不會中了你的
And I am not some starry-eyed waif here to succumb to your...
你下賤的巫術的
Your pelvic sorcery!
不是你想的那樣
That is not what is happening here.
不是吧
No.
快停下
Stop it!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
這爬蟲什么都不懂  還說三道四的
This vermin speaks of affairs he knows nothing about!
-我說的都是事實  -他根本不尊重我
- That is true! - He has no respect!
-這也是事實  -慢著  慢著
- That is also true! - Hold on! Hold on!
你再叫我爬蟲試試  傻大個
Keep calling me vermin, tough guy!
你和別人一樣都只會嘲笑我
You just wanna laugh at me like everyone else!
火箭  你喝醉了  沒人嘲笑你
Rocket, you're drunk. All right? No one's laughing at you.
他覺得我是什么可笑的東西  他說的
He thinks I'm some stupid thing! He does!
我也不想被改造啊
Well, I didn't ask to get made!
我也不想被大卸八塊
I didn't ask to be torn apart,
然后被拆了又裝
and put back together, over and over
最后變成什么
and turned into some...
什么小怪物
Some little monster!
火箭  沒人叫你怪物
Rocket, no one's calling you a monster.
他叫我爬蟲
He called me "Vermin"!
她叫我耗子
She called me "Rodent"!
讓我們瞧瞧
Let's see if you can laugh
給你臉上來個四五發  你還笑不笑得出
after five or six good shots to your frickin' face!
別  別  別  別
No, no, no, no!
四十億啊  火箭
Four billion units! Rocket!
想想吧  冷靜點
Come on, man. Hey!
忍一忍  再受一晚上的罪
Suck it up for one more lousy night
你就有錢了
and you're rich.
好吧
Fine.
我可不保證這事完了后
But I can't promise, when all this is over
我不會把你們這群混蛋全殺了
I'm not gonna kill every last one of you jerks.
看到沒  這就是為什么你們都沒朋友
See? That's exactly why none of you have any friends!
跟別的人才認識五秒
Five seconds after you meet somebody,
你就想著要殺了他們了
you're already trying to kill them!
我們穿過了半個星系來到這
We have travelled, halfway across the quadrant.
連羅南的毫毛都沒傷著
And Ronan is no closer to being dead.
-德拉克斯  -讓他去
- Drax! - Let him go.
我們不需要他
We don't need him.
卡魔拉女士
Milady Gamora.
我過來接你去見我主人
I'm here to fetch you for my master.
這里一點也不詭異
Okay, this isn't creepy at all.
我們的館藏珍品在整個星系是最多的
We house the galaxy's largest collection
動物  遺骸  不同物種應有盡有
of fauna, relics, and species of all manner.
容我為你們介紹
I present to you,
坦利亞·蒂萬  收藏者
Taneleer Tivan, The Collector.
親愛的卡魔拉
My dear Gamora.
能見到本尊真是榮幸
How wonderful to meet in the flesh.
省掉這些繁文縟節吧  蒂萬
Let's bypass the formalities, Tivan.
我們有你要的東西
We have what we discussed.
那邊那個是什么東西
What is that thing there?
我是格魯特
I am Groot.
我從來沒想到能遇見個格魯特
I never thought I'd meet a Groot.
先生
Sir...
請務必把您的尸體賣給我
You must allow me to pay you now
我現在就付款
so that I may own your carcass.
當然了  要等您死后
At the moment of your death, of course.
我是格魯特
I am Groot.
怎么  給你拿去做個椅子嗎
Why, so he could turn you into a frickin' chair?
這是你的寵物嗎
That's your pet?
-他的什么  -蒂萬
- His what? - Tivan.
我們穿越大半個銀河系  取來了靈球
We have been halfway around the galaxy, retrieving this Orb.
非常好  那么
Very well, then.
讓我看看你們帶來的東西
Let us see what you brought.
三塊柯尼斯電池  七箱科他蒂種子
Three quarnyx batteries, seven cases of Cotati seeds.
不  要七箱  上次你寄過來的
No, cases. Last time, you sent me...
你得幫我傳達個信息
You shall send a message for me.
我的新朋友們
My new friends.
在宇宙開創之前
Before creation itself,
一共有六個奇點
there were six singularities.
然后宇宙大爆炸創造了萬物
Then the universe exploded into existence,
這六個奇點的殘留物
and the remnants of these systems
被收集起來凝煉成寶石
were forged into concentrated ingots.
稱作無限寶石
Infinity Stones.
這些寶石似乎
These stones, it seems,
只有擁有非凡的力量
can only be brandished
才能駕馭
by beings of extraordinary strength.
請看
Observe.
這些攜帶者借助寶石能摧毀整個文明
These carriers can use the Stone to mow down entire civilizations
跟收麥子一樣易如反掌
like wheat in a field.
我已經快嚇尿了
There's a little pee coming out of me right now.
曾經有那么一次
Once, for a moment,
一個組織成功地共同控制了這股能量
a group was able to share the energy amongst themselves,
但即使是他們也很快被這力量摧毀了
but even they were quickly destroyed by it.
太美了
Beautiful.
無與倫比
Beyond compare.
我們都沉醉其中了  白毛
We're all very fascinated, whitey.
但是快給錢
But we'd like to get paid.
你們希望用什么方式付款
How would you like to get paid?
你說呢  花花公子  當然是現金
What do you think, fancy man? Units!
很好
Very well, then.
卡瑞娜
Carina.
別靠近
Stand back.
我再也不要做你的奴隸了
I will no longer be your slave!
不
No!
我了個
What the...
我怎么會相信蒂萬
How could I think Tivan
知道如何控制宇宙靈球里的東西
could contain whatever was within the Orb?
你還拿著是要做什么
What do you still have it for?
不然怎么辦  留在那兒嗎
What are we gonna do, leave it in there?
你竟然還裝進自己的荷包里了
I can't believe you had that in your purse!
這是個背包  不是荷包
It's not a purse, it's a knapsack!
我們必須把這個交給新星軍團
We have to bring this to the Nova Corps.
他們可能知道如何控制它
There's a chance they can contain it.
你在開玩笑嗎
Are you kidding me?
我們正在被新星軍團通緝
We're wanted by the Nova Corps.
把它交給羅南就是了
Just give it to Ronan!
然后幫他毀了整個銀河系嗎
So he can destroy the galaxy?
怎么了你  突然變成圣人了嗎
What are you, some saint all of a sudden?
銀河系幫過你嗎
What has the galaxy ever done for you?
你為什么想救它
Why would you wanna save it?
因為我就生活在這里面啊
Because I'm one of the idiots who lives in it!
彼得  聽我說
Peter, listen to me.
絕不能讓寶石落入羅南之手
We cannot allow the Stone to fall into Ronan's hands.
我們現在就回你飛船
We have to go back to your ship,
然后送去新星
and deliver it to Nova.
好的  就這樣  你說得對
Right, right, okay. I think you're right.
或者我們可以把它交給某個
Or we could give it to somebody
不會逮捕我們的
who's not going to arrest us,
大好人
who's really nice
然后大賺一筆
for a whole lot of money.
我覺得這是個
I think it's a really good
能兩全其美的好方法
balance between both of your points of view.
你太卑鄙
You're despicable.
太無恥
Dishonorable.
毫無信用
Faithless!
-不  -終于
- No. - At last!
我要面對我的仇敵并且親手解決他了
I shall meet my foe and destroy him.
是你叫來了羅南
You called Ronan?
奎爾  別想跑  小子
Quill! Don't you move, boy!
你敢跑  別擋道
Don't you move! Get out of the way!
指控者羅南
Ronan the Accuser!
是你傳送的信息嗎
You are the one who transmitted the message?
你殺了我妻子
You killed my wife.
你殺了我女兒
You killed my daughter!
我都說了  你進不來的
I told you, you can't fit.
在這兒等我回來
Now, wait here. I'll be back.
是卡魔拉  她帶著宇宙靈球逃走了
It is Gamora. She is escaping with the Orb.
不
No!
星云
Nebula,
去奪回宇宙靈球
retrieve the Orb.
寶石在最前面那個作業艙里
The Stone is in the furthest pod.
擊落它
Bring it down!
火箭  掩護卡魔拉到米拉諾號
Rocket, keep them off Gamora until she gets to the Milano.
怎么掩護  這上面又沒有武器
How? We've got no weaponry on these things.
這些作業艙都是工業級的
These pods are industrial grade.
基本上堅不可摧
They're nearly indestructible.
那也吃不消死靈炮啊
Not against necroblasts, they're not.
我可不是那個意思
That's not what I'm saying.
借你飛船用一用
Let me borrow your ride.
我不記得殺過你家人
I don't recall killing your family.
大概也不會記得殺過你
I doubt I'll remember killing you, either.
奎爾  我被困住了  到不了米拉諾號
Quill, I'm trapped. I can't make it to the Milano.
只能沖去外層空間了
I have to head out.
等等  這些作業艙不能飛到外層空間去
Wait! These things aren't meant to go out there.
你太讓我失望了  姐姐
You are a disappointment, sister.
在所有姐妹當中
Of all our siblings,
我最不討厭的就是你
I hated you least.
星云  別這樣
Nebula, please.
如果羅南得到了寶石
If Ronan gets this stone
-他會殺光我們所有人  -不是所有人
- He'll kill us all. - Not all.
你活不到那時候
You will already be dead.
羅南  東西到手了
Ronan, it is done.
奎爾  算了
Quill, come on.
她的身體改造過  大概能撐幾分鐘
Her body mods should keep her alive a couple more minutes,
可我們沒辦法救她
but there's nothing we can do for her.
這些作業艙在外面堅持不了多久的
These pods aren't meant to be out here.
很快  我們也會像她一樣
In a second, we're gonna be in the same boat.
去他的
Aw, damn it.
奎爾
Quill?
勇度  勇度
Yondu! Yondu.
我是奎爾
This is Quill!
-我現在的坐標是227K324  -奎爾
- My coordinates are 227K324. - Quill.
奎爾  你在干什么
Quill, what are you doing?
就在無存知地外面
Just outside Knowhere.
如果你在的話  就來抓我吧
If you're there, come get me.
我隨你處置
I'm all yours.
奎爾  別犯傻
Quill, don't be ridiculous.
回你的作業艙里去
Get back into your pod!
里面裝不下兩個人  你會死的
You can't fit two people in there. You're gonna die.
你馬上就會死的
You'll die in seconds!
奎爾
Quill.
Quill?
怎么了
What happened?
我看見你漂浮在外面
I saw you out there.
我也不知道自己怎么了
I don't know what came over me.
我不能眼睜睜讓你死
But I couldn't let you die.
我突然感受到了內心深處的一種
I found something inside of myself.
一種
Something
難以置信的英雄氣概
incredibly heroic.
我不是在夸自己
I mean, not to brag,
可是  客觀地說
but, objectively...
宇宙靈球呢
Where's the Orb?
他們把宇宙靈球搶走了
It's... Well, they got the Orb.
什么
What?
歡迎回家  彼得
Welcome home, Peter.
蠢貨  全是無可救藥的蠢貨
Blasted idiot. They're all idiots!
奎爾竟然自投羅網了
Quill just got himself captured.
要不是你
None of this ever would have
一意孤行  非要去單挑羅南
happened if you didn't try to single-handedly
這一切都不會發生
take on a frickin' army!
你說得沒錯
You're right.
我是個傻瓜
I was a fool.
所有的憤怒
All the anger,
所有的怨氣
all the rage,
都是為了掩飾我的傷痛
was just to cover my loss.
"我的老婆孩子都死了"
Boo-hoo-hoo. "My wife and child are dead."
我才不在乎這有多殘忍
I don't care if it's mean!
誰家沒死過人
Everybody's got dead people.
不代表你就有理由讓大家
It's no excuse to get everybody else
陪你一起送死
dead along the way!
好了  格魯特  羅南拿到了寶石
Come on, Groot. Ronan has the Stone.
我們現在唯一能做的
The only chance we got
就是趕緊飛往宇宙另一頭去
is to get to the other side of the universe
越快越好
as fast as we can and maybe,
也許趁著那神經病還沒打過來
just maybe, we'll be able to live full lives
能安穩的過一輩子
before that whack-job ever gets there.
我是格魯特
I am Groot.
救他們  怎么救
Save them? How?
我是格魯特
I am Groot.
我知道他們是我們唯一的朋友
I know they're the only friends that we ever had,
可他們現在落在掠奪者軍隊手里
but there's an army of Ravagers around them.
我們只有兩個人
And there's only two of us!
是三個
Three.
我都被你們氣得
You're making me
只能  拿草
beat...up
撒氣了
grass!
宇宙靈球已經在我手里了
The Orb is in my possession,
我說到做到
as I promised.
把它送到我這里來
Bring it to me.
沒錯  這是我們之前約定好的
Yes, that was our agreement.
我幫你拿來宇宙靈球
Bring you the Orb,
你幫我毀滅山達爾
and you will destroy Xandar for me.
不過  既然我知道了它裝有無限寶石
However, now that I know it contains an Infinity Stone,
我很好奇我還要你做什么
I wonder what use I have for you.
小子
Boy,
你最好給我想清楚了
I would reconsider your current course.
主人  你不能這么做
Master! You cannot!
滅霸是這宇宙中最強大的存在
Thanos is the most powerful being in the universe.
不再是了
Not anymore.
你竟然叫我"小子"
You call me "Boy!"
我會代表克里
I will unfurl
對千年來山達爾的所作所為進行審判
1,000 years of Kree justice on Xandar,
讓它消失殆盡
and burn it to its core!
之后  滅霸
Then, Thanos,
我就去找你算賬
I am coming for you.
毀滅山達爾之后  你會殺掉我父親嗎
After Xandar, you are going to kill my father?
你想反抗我嗎
You dare to oppose me?
你也看到他對我做了些什么
You see what he has turned me into.
你殺了他  我會再幫你毀滅一千個星球
If you kill him, I will help you destroy a thousand planets.
你敢背叛我?
You betray me?
偷我的錢?
Steal my money?
住手  放開他
Stop it! Leave him alone!
你小時候剛被我撿到的時候
When I picked you up as a kid,
這些小子想吃了你
these boys wanted to eat you.
他們還沒嘗過地星人的味道呢
They ain't never tasted Terran before.
是我救了你
I saved your life!
還有完沒完啊  天哪
Will you shut up about that? God!
二十年了  一直給我說這些陳芝麻爛谷子
Twenty years, you been throwing that in my face,
好像沒有吃掉我是件多么偉大的事
like it's some great thing, not eating me.
正常人哪會每天想著吃人啊
Normal people don't even think about eating someone else!
不吃我難道我還得謝你嗎
Much less that person having to be grateful for it!
是你劫持了我
You abducted me, man.
把我從家里擄走  害我無親無故
You stole me from my home and from my family.
你他媽才不是因為在乎你們地星
You don't give a damn about your Terra!
你害怕
You're scared
不過是因為內心太懦弱了
because you're soft in here.
這里  就在這里
Here, right here!
勇度
Yondu!
聽我說
Listen to me.
羅南掌握著一塊叫無限寶石的東西
Ronan has something called an Infinity Stone.
我知道他手里有什么  小姑娘
I know what he's got, girl.
那你就該知道  我們必須把它搶回來
Then you know we must get it back!
他會用寶石摧毀掉山達爾
He's gonna use it to wipe out Xandar.
我們得警告他們
We have to warn them.
否則無數的人會因此喪命
Billions of people will perish.
她就是這樣給你洗腦的嗎  小子
Is that what she's been filling your head with, boy?
多愁善感
Sentiment?
蛆蟲一樣蠶食掉你的大腦
Eating away your brain like maggots!
就這樣吧
That's it.
不
No!
抱歉了  小子
Sorry, boy.
身為隊長  必須殺一儆百
But a captain's gotta teach his men
讓手下知道背叛會是什么下場
what happens to those what cross him.
隊長要以身作則
Captain's gotta teach stuff!
如果你現在殺了我
If you kill me now,
就別想做成這輩子最大一筆生意了
you are saying goodbye to the biggest score you have ever seen.
無限寶石嗎
The Stone?
你最好能想出個別的
I hope you got something better than that.
沒有人能從羅南手里偷東西
Because ain't nobody stealing from Ronan.
我們有秘密武器
We got a ringer.
是嗎
Is that right?
她清楚有關羅南的一切
She knows everything there is to know about Ronan.
他的艦隊
His ships,
他的部下
his army.
他也有弱點
He's vulnerable.
你覺得怎么樣  勇度
Hey, what do you say, Yondu?
我和你  還跟以前一樣  攜手作戰
Me and you, taking down a mark side-by-side, like the old days.
放開他
Let him go!
你小子一向有種
You always did have a scrote, boy!
所以我當時才留你在身邊
That's why I kept you on as a young'un.
隊長  這種攻擊不痛不癢的
Captain, the shot was non-damaging.
請注意  蠢貨們
Attention, idiots.
飛船上這個瘋子手里拿著的是強子槍
The lunatic on top of this craft is holding a Hadron Enforcer.
我獨家設計的武器
It's a weapon of my own design.
這是在搞什么
What the hell?
要是你們不趕緊交出我朋友
If you don't hand over our companions now,
他就把你們的飛船轟出個新鮮的洞
he's gonna tear your ship a new one.
又大又新鮮的洞
A very big new one!
-老子才不買你的賬  -我倒數五下
- I ain't buyin' it. - I'm giving you to the count of five.
-5  4  3  -別  等一下
- 5, 4, 3... - No! Wait, hold on!
火箭  是我  真是的
Rocket, it's me, for God sakes!
已經談攏了  我們沒事了
We figured it out! We're fine!
奎爾  怎么回事
Hey, Quill. What's going on?
這就叫"談攏了"
You call that "Figured it out"?
要從那群把我們
We're gonna rob the guys
打得屁滾尿流的家伙手里搶東西
who just beat us senseless.
你還有臉說屁滾尿流
You want to talk about senseless?
你到底是想救我們還是想把我們炸飛
How about trying to save us by blowing us up?
他們要是不交出你們
We were only gonna blow you up
我才會把他們炸飛
if they didn't turn you over!
你只數五下
And how on earth were they gonna turn us over
他們哪有時間交出我們
when you only gave them a count of five?
我們又沒空考慮倒數時間
We didn't have time to work out the minutiae
那些細節
of the plan.
我們為朋友兩肋插刀就這下場
This is what we get for acting altruistically.
-我是格魯特  -他們根本不領情
- I am Groot. - They are ungrateful.
重點是
What's important now
我們說服了掠奪者軍隊
is we get the Ravagers' army
幫我們拯救山達爾
to help us save Xandar.
然后我們再把寶石交給勇度
So we can give the Stone to Yondu
好讓他賣給一個更邪惡的家伙嗎
who's just gonna sell to somebody even worse?
這個之后再議
We'll figure that part out later.
我們必須阻止羅南
We have to stop Ronan.
怎么阻止
How?
我有個計劃
I have a plan.
你有個計劃?
You've got a plan?
沒錯
Yes.
首先  那句話是我說的
First of all, you're copying me from
-你算是抄襲  -哪有
- when I said I had a plan. - No, I'm not.
這話誰都會說
People say that all the time.
又沒什么特別的
It's not that unique of a thing to say.
其次  我不相信你有什么計劃
Secondly, I don't even believe you have a plan.
我有一部分計劃
I have part of a plan!
一部分是多少
What percentage of a plan do you have?
鑒于你在無存知地的表現
You don't get to ask questions
你沒有權利提問
after the nonsense you pulled on Knowhere.
我可救了奎爾
I just saved Quill.
我們已經討論過了
We've already established
你們想炸了我乘坐的飛船  那可不是在救我
that you destroying the ship that I'm on is not saving me.
我們什么時候討論過了
When did we establish it?
就幾秒鐘以前
Like three seconds ago!
我沒在仔細聽  那會兒正走神
I wasn't listening. I was thinking of something else.
她說得沒錯  你沒有發表意見的權利
She's right. You don't get an opinion.
你有百分之多少的計劃
What percentage?
我不知道  百分之十二吧
I don't know. Twelve percent.
百分之十二?
Twelve percent?
你笑得真假
That's a fake laugh.
-是真的  -太假了
- It's real! - Totally fake.
這是我這輩子笑得最真實
That is the most real, authentic,
最歇斯底里的一次了
hysterical laugh of my entire life
因為你這是狗屁計劃
because that is not a plan.
只能算是一個想法
It's barely a concept.
你站到他們那一邊去了嗎
You're taking their side?
我是格魯特
I am Groot.
是比百分之十一要強點  又怎樣
So what, it's better than 11%?
你那狗屁計劃能有什么用
What the hell does that have to do with anything?
謝謝你  格魯特  謝謝
Thank you, Groot. Thank you.
格魯特是你們當中唯一一個明事理的
See? Groot's the only one of you who has a clue.
伙伴們
Guys.
拜托
Come on.
勇度馬上就要過來了
Yondu is gonna be here in two seconds.
他還想聽聽我們的大計劃呢
He expects to hear this big plan of ours.
我需要你們的幫助
I need your help.
看看我們
I look around at us.
知道我看到了什么嗎
You know what I see?
一群失敗者
Losers.
我們就像
I mean, like,
一群失魂落魄的家伙
folks who have lost stuff.
確實如此  我們所有人都失去過
And we have. Man, we have. All of us.
失去了家
Our homes,
失去了家人
our families,
失去了正常的生活
normal lives.
沒錯  生活本來就是付出比回報更多
And, usually, life takes more than it gives.
可今天不是
But not today.
今天我們得到了眷顧
Today, it's given us something.
生活給了我們一個機會
It has given us a chance.
什么機會
To do what?
去拼一回
To give a shit.
僅此一回
For once.
不要逃避
Not run away.
羅南要屠殺無數無辜的生命
I, for one, am not gonna stand by and watch
而我  絕不會袖手旁觀
as Ronan wipes out billions of innocent lives.
可是  奎爾  想要阻止羅南
But, Quill, stopping Ronan,
是不可能的
it's impossible.
你是在叫我們去送死
You're asking us to die.
是啊  應該是吧
Yeah, I guess I am.
奎爾
Quill.
我活了這么久  只跟敵人打過交道
I have lived most my life surrounded by my enemies.
我愿意和朋友共生死
I will be grateful to die among my friends.
你是個有擔當的男人  奎爾
You are an honorable man, Quill.
我愿意跟你并肩作戰
I will fight beside you.
最后
And in the end,
我就能和我的妻女團聚了
I will see my wife and daughter again.
我是格魯特
I am Groot.
隨你們吧  反正本來我也活不長
What the hell. I don't got that long a lifespan, anyway.
我也站起來了  你們滿意了吧
Now I'm standing. Y'all happy?
現在我們都站起來了
We're all standing up now.
一群傻缺  站成個圈圈
Bunch of jackasses, standing in a circle.
寶石會對任何有機體產生反應
The Stone reacts to anything organic.
目標越大  威力越強
The bigger the target, the bigger the power surge.
羅南只需要讓寶石
All Ronan's got to do is
接觸到星球的表面  它就會毀掉一切
touch the Stone to the planet's surface and zap.
所有的植物  動物
All plants, animals,
-新星軍團  -一切都將被毀滅
- Nova Corps. - Everything will die.
所以不能讓羅南登陸
So Ronan does not make the surface.
火箭帶領一隊人馬在暗黑星號右舷
Rocket will lead a team to blow a hole
轟開一個洞
in the Dark Aster's starboard hull.
這樣我們和勇度的飛船就可以攻進去了
Then, our craft and Yondu's will enter.
里面有上百個薩卡士兵把守吧
Won't there be hundreds of Sakaaran soldiers inside?
薩卡士兵都是紙做的
I think of Sakaaran as paper people.
他們一旦得知我們登陸了
Once they know we're on board,
羅南會關上艙內的安全門
Ronan will isolate himself
把自己隔離起來
behind impenetrable security doors on deck.
我可以通過破壞動力系統解鎖
Which I can disable by dismantling the power source.
接著我們進到駕駛艙
We'll make it to the flight deck,
用強子槍把羅南轟上天
and I'll use the Hadron Enforcer to kill Ronan.
羅南一死我們就回收寶石
Once Ronan is dead, we will retrieve the Stone.
記得要把它裝進這些裝置里
Use these devices to contain it.
別直接觸摸
If you touch it,
不然小命就沒了
it will kill you.
我會聯絡之前逮捕過我們的新星警官
I'll contact one of the Nova officers who arrested us.
但愿他們相信我們是來幫忙的
Hopefully, they'll believe we're there to help.
正在呼入
彼得·奎爾
完成計劃還需要最后一步
There's one more thing we need to complete the plan.
那家伙的眼睛
That guy's eye.
不  瞎說什么呢
No! No, we don't.
我們不需要那家伙的眼睛
No, we don't need that guy's eye.
不  說真的  對我來說相當重要呢
No, seriously, I need it! It's important to me.
已發現羅南艦隊
Ronan's fleet has been spotted,
預計十五分鐘后抵達
and will arrive in T-minus fifteen minutes.
聽好了  小子
Remember, boy.
這事完了之后
At the end of all this,
寶石歸我
I get the Stone.
敢耍我就砍死你們
You cross me, we kill you all.
準備大干一場吧  小子們
Let's go get 'em, boys!
這計劃爛死了
This is a terrible plan.
不是你說要和朋友共生死的嗎
Hey, you're the one who said you wanted to die among friends.
新星至尊
Nova Prime.
一個掠奪者剛剛給我傳達了一則消息
I received a transmission from one of the Ravagers.
他說羅南得到了一顆什么無限寶石
He says Ronan's in possession of something called an Infinity Stone
正沖著山達爾來
and he's headed toward Xandar.
老天爺
Good God.
不過是個幌子  別忘了他是罪犯
It's a trick. He's a criminal.
他有說我們為什么要相信他嗎
Did he say why we should believe him?
他說他們一幫人剛剛越獄
He said his crew just escaped from prison,
如果不是為了拯救山達爾沒理由冒險
so he'd have no other reason to risk coming to Xandar to help.
他說他確實是個
He says that he's an...
"混球"
"A-hole."
但不是一個
But he's not...
引用他原話就是
and I'm quoting him, here,
"徹頭徹尾的混蛋"
"100% a dick."
你信他嗎
Do you believe him?
我也不知道有沒有徹頭徹尾的混蛋  夫人
I don't know that I believe anyone is 100% a dick, ma'am.
我是問  你相信他是來幫忙的嗎
I mean, do you believe that he is here to help?
信啊
Yeah.
不明艦隊逼近中
A fleet approaches.
看起來像是掠奪者
They appear to be Ravagers.
開火
Fire!
掩護就位
Cover it down.
全體下潛
Submerge!
火箭  快上
Rocket, hurry!
全體飛行員下潛
All pilots, dive!
他們在我們正下方
They're beneath us!
疏散全體市民
Evacuate the city.
我們的首要任務是確保人民安全撤離
Our priority is to get our people away from the battle.
全速推進  動作快
Forward thrust, now!
加把勁兒
Come on!
奎爾  勇度  趁現在
Quill! Yondu! Now!
媽的
Aw, hell!
我被擊落了  奎爾
I'm going down, Quill!
別給我耍花招  小子
No more games with me, boy!
完事之后我們再會
I'll see you at the end of this!
他們人太多了  火箭
There are too many of them, Rocket!
我們沒法突圍
We'll never make it up there!
彼得·奎爾
Peter Quill.
我是新星軍團的丹納利安·薩爾
This is Denarian Saal of the Nova Corps.
先聲明一下  我始終認為不該相信你
For the record, I advised against trusting you here.
看來我的"混蛋"消息他們收到了
They got my "Dick" Message!
用事實證明我錯了吧
Prove me wrong.
爽
Yes!
夠嗨
我們和凱文·貝肯差不多厲害吧
We're just like Kevin Bacon.
右舷核心部位受創
The starboard kern has been breached!
他們闖進來了
We have been boarded.
繼續向前推進
Continue our approach.
但是新星軍團也摻合進來了
But the Nova Corps have engaged.
著陸之后一切就都不是問題了
None of that will matter once we reach the surface.
關閉所有安全門
Seal security doors!
趕緊
Now!
別擋老娘的路
Get out of my way!
老天
Oh, man.
所有新星飛行員聽令
All Nova pilots,
全體對接形成封鎖網
interlock and form a blockade.
務必阻止暗黑星號著陸
The Dark Aster must not reach the ground.
已鎖入
Locked in!
Locked in.
已鎖入
We're locked in.
我什么都看不見
I can barely see.
你什么時候學了這一招
When did you learn to do that?
我猜答案肯定是
Pretty sure the answer is
"我是格魯特"
"I am Groot."
飛行甲板就在前方300米處
The flight deck is 300 meters this way.
我希望你們知道
I want you all to know that
感謝你們  不在意我的魯莽之舉
I am grateful for your acceptance
依然接受我
after my blunders.
再次有朋友相伴的感覺...
It is pleasing to once again have...
真棒
friends.
奎爾  你是我朋友
You, Quill, are my friend.
謝了
Thanks.
這顆蠢樹也是我朋友
This dumb tree, he is my friend.
還有這個綠婊子也
And this green whore, she, too...
給我閉嘴
You must stop!
卡魔拉  看看你干的好事
Gamora, look at what you have done.
你還是一如既往的軟弱
You have always been weak.
愚蠢  背信棄...
You stupid, traitorous...
不要這么跟我朋友說話
Nobody talks to my friends like that.
你們去飛行甲板
Head to the flight deck.
我去切斷安全門的動力
I'll shut down the power to the security doors.
勇度·尤冬塔
Yondu Udonta.
命令自己的手下向新星軍團投降
Order your men to turn on the Nova Corps.
玩夠了沒  掠奪者
Enough nonsense, Ravager!
你的死期到...
Time to die...
星云  別這樣
Nebula, please.
夠了  死靈艦隊飛行員
Enough of this. Necrocraft pilots,
開始自我獻祭吧
enact immolation initiative.
他們沖下去轟炸城市了
They're dive-bombing the city!
丹納利安·薩爾  需要解除連鎖嗎
Denarian Saal, should we break formation?
不行  保持陣形
No! Hold your positions.
拖住羅南  薩爾
Keep Ronan up there, Saal.
下面市民的安全交給我們了
We'll take care of the people down here.
我居然要聽命于一只小倉鼠
I can't believe I'm taking orders from a hamster.
星爵
Star-Lord.
終于記住了
Finally.
你個卑鄙的賊
You thief!
你們休想攻到羅南那兒去
You will never make it to Ronan.
在死靈艦著陸之前就把他們轟下來
Everybody shoot them before they hit the ground.
來吧
Come on!
手指劃過喉嚨就是殺人
Finger to the throat means death.
我用比喻了
Metaphor.
差不多吧
Yeah, sorta.
不是吧
Oh, no.
山達爾
Xandar!
接受制裁吧
You stand accused.
可悲的和平條約也救不了你們了
Your wretched peace treaty will not save you now.
跟條約一起葬身火海吧
It is the tinder on which you burn.
火箭
Rocket!
堅持住  薩爾  再堅...
Hold on, Saal, just...
奎爾  你得快點了
Quill, you gotta hurry.
市民倒是都被疏散了
The city's been evacuated,
可我們還在苦戰呢
but we're getting our asses kicked down here.
卡魔拉還沒把門打開
Gamora hasn't opened the door!
星云
Nebula!
妹妹  幫我們一起打敗羅南吧
Sister, help us fight Ronan.
你很清楚他就是個瘋子
You know he's crazy.
你們倆都是瘋子
I know you're both crazy.
不
No!
什么鬼...
What the...?
滾出去
Get out!
你成功了
You did it!
之前我錯了
I was mistaken.
我確實記得你家人
I do remember your family.
她們臨死時的叫聲
Their screams were
那么可悲  我
pitiful. I...
不  格魯特
No, Groot!
別這樣
You can't.
你會死的
You'll die.
為什么要這么做
Why are you doing this?
為什么
Why?
我們
We...
是
are...
格魯特
Groot.
真是個白癡
I called him an idiot.
是你殺了格魯特
You killed Groot!
看吧
Behold!
看這支銀河護衛隊
Your guardians of the galaxy.
你們護衛了什么
What fruit have they wrought?
現在我終于得償所愿
Only that my father and his father
為我父親和爺爺報了仇
shall finally know vengeance.
山達爾的子民
People of Xandar,
背棄你們卑微的信仰
the time has come to rejoice
迎接我的時刻到了
and renounce your paltry gods!
你們即將得到救贖
Your salvation is at hand.
聽這幾句
Listen to these words.
用力舞起來
Now bring it down hard!
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
比舞啊  老兄  就我們倆
Dance-off, Bro. Me and you.
卡魔拉
Gamora.
委婉拒絕  收回邀請
Subtle. Take it back.
你到底在搞什么鬼
What are you doing?
分你的心啊  大蠢蛋
I'm distracting you, you big turd blossom.
不
No!
彼得  握住我的手
Peter! Take my hand!
握住我的手  彼得
Take my hand, Peter.
媽媽
Mom.
握住我的手
Take my hand!
你們只是凡人
You're mortal!
怎么可能
How?
你不是說過嗎  婊子
You said it yourself, bitch.
我們可是銀河護衛隊
We're the Guardians of the Galaxy.
不錯  不錯
Well, well, well.
好一場光影盛宴
Quite the light show.
大團圓結局啊
Ain't this sweet.
不過在你們嘿咻嘿咻之前
But you got some business to attend to
先給我把正事辦了
before all the nookie-nookie starts.
彼得  你不能給他
Peter, you can't. Peter.
你得三思  勇度
You gotta reconsider this, Yondu.
我不知道你要把它賣給誰
I don't know who you're selling this to,
不過能讓宇宙安定平穩的唯一方法
but the only way the universe can survive
就是把它交給新星軍團保管
is if you give it to the Nova Corps.
都說我長得像菩薩
I may be as pretty as an angel,
可我沒有菩薩心腸
but I sure as hell ain't one.
快交給我吧  孩子
Hand it over, son.
勇度
Yondu.
決不能打開宇宙靈球  你知道的吧
Do not open that Orb. You know that, right?
你也看見它的威力了
You've seen what it does to people.
奎爾這小子還挺懂事
Yeah, Quill turned out okay.
當初沒有按他爹的要求把他送過去
It's probably good we didn't deliver him to his dad
也許是個正確的決定
like we was hired to do.
是啊  他爹就是個混球
Yeah, that guy was a jackass.
等他發現宇宙靈球被我掉包了
He is gonna be so pissed when he realizes
非氣炸不可
I switched out the Orb on him.
他一定會砍死你  彼得
He was gonna kill you, Peter.
是啊
Oh, I know.
不過他也算是我唯一的親人了
But he was about the only family I had.
不
No.
不止是他
He wasn't.
你們怎么連這個都知道
Why would you even know this?
當初抓你回來后
When we arrested you,
我們發現你的神經系統有些異常
we noticed an anomaly in your nervous system,
于是幫你做了檢查
so we had it checked out.
所以我不是地星人
I'm not Terran?
有一半血統來自地星
You are half Terran.
你母親是地球人  至于你父親
Your mother was of Earth. Your father, well,
他是某種我們從未接觸過的遠古生靈
he's something very ancient we've never seen here before.
怪不得
That could be why
你握著寶石那么久卻沒事
you were able to hold the Stone for as long as you did.
你的朋友們來齊了
Your friends have arrived.
我謹代表新星軍團
On behalf of the Nova Corps,
向你們致以最真誠的謝意
we'd like to express our profound gratitude
謝謝你們拯救了山達爾
for your help in saving Xandar.
你們可以跟隨丹納利安·戴
If you will follow Denarian Dey,
他有東西要帶你們看
he has something to show you.
謝謝了  新星至尊
Thank you, Nova Prime.
你幫妻女報了仇
Your wife and child shall rest well
現在她們能安息了
knowing that you have avenged them.
是啊
Yes.
不過說到底羅南只是個傀儡
Of course, Ronan was only a puppet.
得殺掉滅霸才算報仇
It's really Thanos I need to kill.
我們想保留它原本的樣子
We tried to keep it as close to the original as possible.
已經盡全力做了相關修復了
We salvaged as much as we could.
我
I...
多謝了
Thank you.
我也有妻兒
I have a family.
多虧你她們才能活下來
They're alive because of you.
你們的犯罪記錄已經被抹掉了
Your criminal records have also been expunged.
不過還是得提醒你們
However, I have to warn
遵紀守法才是好公民
you against breaking any laws in the future.
問一下
Question.
如果我拿了一件很想要的
What if I see something that I want to take,
剛好又屬于別人的東西呢
and it belongs to someone else?
你會被逮捕
You will be arrested.
可如果我比物主更想要那東西呢
But what if I want it more than the person who has it?
-還是違法的  -說不通啊
- It's still illegal. - That doesn't follow.
我更想要啊  長官  你懂嗎
No, I want it more, sir. Do you understand?
笑什么
What are you laughing at?
干嘛拉我走  我不能和這位先生聊聊嗎
Why? I can't have a discussion with this gentleman?
如果誰把我惹毛了
What if someone does something irksome
然后我決定要抽了他的脊椎呢
and I decide to remove his spine?
那個
That's...
那個應該算謀殺了
That's actually murder.
最惡劣的犯罪之一
It's one of the worst crimes of all.
所以  也是違法的
So... also illegal.
他們會老實待著的  戴
They'll be fine, Dey.
我會看好他們的
I'm gonna keep an eye on 'em.
你
You?
對啊  我
Yeah. Me.
彼得
Peter,
我知道最近幾個月對你來說很痛苦
I know these last few months have been hard for you.
其實我只是要去個更好的地方
But I'm going to a better place.
我會照顧好自己的
And I will be okay.
我會永遠陪在你身邊
And I will always be with you.
你是我生命的曙光
You are the light of my life.
我摯愛的兒子
My precious son.
我的小星爵
My little Star-Lord.
永遠愛你的媽媽
Love, Mom.
勁歌金曲  第二輯
那么接下來做什么呢
So, what should we do next?
干點好事
Something good?
干點壞事
Something bad?
還是都干一點
A bit of both?
你說了算  星爵
We'll follow your lead, Star-Lord.
那就都干一點
Bit of both.
銀河護衛隊
即將歸來
沒有任何浣熊與樹狀生物在拍攝過程中受到傷害
你就隨它那么舔嗎
What do you let it lick you like that for?
霍華德鴨  漫威漫畫角色
惡心
Gross.
好爽
Yeah!
就是有點火辣
But it burns going down.